<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<bank xmlns="https://checkit.clontz.org" version="0.2">
    <title>Calculus III</title>
    <slug>calcIII</slug>
    <url>https://jme2103.github.io/calc3-standards/</url>
    <outcomes>

    <!-- MV - Euclidean Space and Multivariable Functions -->

        <outcome>
            <title>Surfaces and Graphs</title>
            <slug>MV1</slug>
            <path>outcomes/MV/MV1</path>
            <description>
                Use traces and contours to describe the graphs of functions of two variables.
            </description>
        </outcome>
        <outcome>
            <title>Vector Arithmetic</title>
            <slug>MV2</slug>
            <path>outcomes/MV/MV2</path>
            <description>
                Compute and geometrically interpret sums, differences, scalar multiples, and magnitudes of vectors in n-dimensional space.
            </description>
        </outcome>
        <outcome>
            <title>Vector Geometry</title>
            <slug>MV3</slug>
            <path>outcomes/MV/MV3</path>
            <description>
                Use dot products and cross products of vectors to compute quantities of geometric interest, including projections, angles, and areas.
            </description>
        </outcome>
        <outcome>
            <title>Parametrized Lines</title>
            <slug>MV4</slug>
            <path>outcomes/MV/MV4</path>
            <description>
                Determine parametric equations for a line in three-space.
            </description>
        </outcome>
        <outcome>
            <title>Planes</title>
            <slug>MV5</slug>
            <path>outcomes/MV/MV5</path>
            <description>
                Find an equation for a plane in three-space defined either by three non-collinear points or by a point and a normal vector.
            </description>
        </outcome>
        <outcome>
            <title>Intersections</title>
            <slug>MV6</slug>
            <path>outcomes/MV/MV6</path>
            <description>
                Find the intersection of lines and planes.
            </description>
        </outcome>
        <outcome>
            <title>Parameterized Curve</title>
            <slug>MV7</slug>
            <path>outcomes/MV/MV7</path>
            <description>
                Sketch and parameterize portions of oriented curves, including those defined by intersections of surfaces and those which involve circular motions.
            </description>
        </outcome>
        <outcome>
            <title>Derivatives and Curvature</title>
            <slug>MV8</slug>
            <path>outcomes/MV/MV8</path>
            <description>
                Use derivatives to determine, and distinguish among, a parameterized curve’s tangent, speed, velocity, and acceleration.
            </description>
        </outcome>
        <!-- <outcome>
            <title>Equilibrium</title>
            <slug>NC</slug>
            <path>outcomes/NC</path>
            <description>
                Solve vector equations to find the equilibrium state of a system.
            </description>
        </outcome> -->
    
    <!-- PD - Partial Derivatives -->

        <outcome>
            <title>Partial Derivatives</title>
            <slug>PD1</slug>
            <path>outcomes/PD/PD1</path>
            <description>
                Compute the partial derivatives of a given multivariable function up to second order.
            </description>
        </outcome>
        <outcome>
            <title>Tangent Planes</title>
            <slug>PD2</slug>
            <path>outcomes/PD/PD2</path>
            <description>
                Find equations for tangent planes to surfaces expressed as graphs of two-variable functions and as level sets of three-variable functions.
            </description>
        </outcome>
        <outcome>
            <title>Gradients</title>
            <slug>PD3</slug>
            <path>outcomes/PD/PD3</path>
            <description>
                Compute the gradient vector of a two-variable function, give its geometric interpretation with respect both to the contours of the function and to its graph, and use it to calculate directional derivatives in a given direction.
            </description>
        </outcome>
        <outcome>
            <title>Critical Points of Multivariable Functions</title>
            <slug>PD4</slug>
            <path>outcomes/PD/PD4</path>
            <description>
                Use gradient vectors to locate critical points of a multivariable function, and second-order partial derivatives to classify critical points as local maximum, local minimum, saddle point, or degenerate.
            </description>
        </outcome>
        <outcome>
            <title>Multivariable Limits</title>
            <slug>PD5</slug>
            <path>outcomes/PD/PD5</path>
            <description>
                Use algebra, continuity, and polar-coordinate methods to calculate limits of multivariable functions, and use multiple-approach methods to demonstrate when such a limit does not exist.
            </description>
        </outcome>
        <outcome>
            <title>Multivariable Chain Rule</title>
            <slug>PD6</slug>
            <path>outcomes/PD/PD6</path>
            <description>
                Identify all routes of composition when two or more multivariable functions are composed, and use the multivariable chain rule to compute partial derivatives.
            </description>
        </outcome>
        <outcome>
            <title>Higher Dimensional Gradients</title>
            <slug>PD7</slug>
            <path>outcomes/PD/PD7</path>
            <description>
                Compute the gradient vector of a three-variable function, give its geometric interpretation with respect to its level surfaces, and use it to calculate directional derivatives in a given direction.
            </description>
        </outcome>
        <outcome>
            <title>Multivariable Extreme Values</title>
            <slug>PD8</slug>
            <path>outcomes/PD/PD8</path>
            <description>
                Use both critical points and a parametrization of its boundary to find absolute maximum and minimum values of a multivariable function on a closed and bounded domain.
            </description>
        </outcome>
        <outcome>
            <title>Constrained Optimization</title>
            <slug>PD9</slug>
            <path>outcomes/PD/PD9</path>
            <description>
                Use Lagrange multipliers to determine absolute maximum and minimum values of a multivariable function subject to one or more constant constraints.
            </description>
        </outcome>

    <!-- MI - Multiple Integrals -->

        <outcome>
            <title>Planar Regions</title>
            <slug>MI1</slug>
            <path>outcomes/MI/MI1</path>
            <description>
                Describe a given region in the plane using coordinate inequalities in at least two distinct ways.
            </description>
        </outcome>
        <outcome>
            <title>Double Integrals</title>
            <slug>MI2</slug>
            <path>outcomes/MI/MI2</path>
            <description>
                Set up and evaluate double integrals over general regions, using iterated integrals with "tape-measured" bounds.
            </description>
        </outcome>
        <outcome>
            <title>Integrals in Polar Coordinates</title>
            <slug>MI3</slug>
            <path>outcomes/MI/MI3</path>
            <description>
                Use polar coordinates to transform the integrand, the bounds, and the area element of a given double integral.
            </description>
        </outcome>
        <outcome>
            <title>Surface Area</title>
            <slug>MI4</slug>
            <path>outcomes/MI/MI4</path>
            <description>
                Set up double integrals to compute surface areas of portions of parametrized surfaces.
            </description>
        </outcome>
        <outcome>
            <title>Triple Integrals</title>
            <slug>MI5</slug>
            <path>outcomes/MI/MI5</path>
            <description>
                Set up and evaluate triple integrals over general regions using iterated integrals and “tape-measured” bounds.
            </description>
        </outcome>
        <outcome>
            <title>Integrals in Cylindrical and Spherical Coordinates</title>
            <slug>MI6</slug>
            <path>outcomes/MI/MI6</path>
            <description>
                Use cylindrical and spherical coordinates to transform the integrand, the bounds, and the volume element of a given triple integral.
            </description>
        </outcome>
        <outcome>
            <title>Change of Variables</title>
            <slug>MI7</slug>
            <path>outcomes/MI/MI7</path>
            <description>
                Use change of variables simplify a multiple integral.
            </description>
        </outcome>

        <!-- VC - Vector Calculus -->

        <outcome>
            <title>Vector Fields</title>
            <slug>VC1</slug>
            <path>outcomes/VC/VC1</path>
            <description>
                Sketch and identify vector fields in two and three dimensions, including gradient vector fields of two- and three-variable functions.
            </description>
        </outcome>
        <outcome>
            <title>Line Integrals</title>
            <slug>VC2</slug>
            <path>outcomes/VC/VC2</path>
            <description>
                Directly compute the line integral of a vector field over a given oriented path.
            </description>
        </outcome>
        <outcome>
            <title>Fundamental Theorem for Line Integrals</title>
            <slug>VC3</slug>
            <path>outcomes/VC/VC3</path>
            <description>
                Determine if vector fields are gradients, find scalar potential functions for gradient fields, and apply the fundamental theorem of calculus for line integrals.
            </description>
        </outcome>
        <outcome>
            <title>Green's Theorem</title>
            <slug>VC4</slug>
            <path>outcomes/VC/VC4</path>
            <description>
                Use Green's Theorem to relate the total circulation of a vector field along a closed path to a double integral.
            </description>
        </outcome>
        <outcome>
            <title>Curl of a Vector Field</title>
            <slug>VC5</slug>
            <path>outcomes/VC/VC5</path>
            <description>
                Compute the scalar curl of a two-dimensional vector field, compute the vector curl of a three-dimensional vector field, and use notions of circulation to predict whether the scalar curl of a two-dimensional vector field is positive, negative, or zero.
            </description>
        </outcome>
        <outcome>
            <title>Divergence of a Vector Field</title>
            <slug>VC6</slug>
            <path>outcomes/VC/VC6</path>
            <description>
                Compute the divergence of a vector field and use notions of flux to predict whether the divergence of a given vector field is positive, negative, or zero.
            </description>
        </outcome>
        <outcome>
            <title>Flux Integrals</title>
            <slug>VC7</slug>
            <path>outcomes/VC/VC7</path>
            <description>
                Directly compute the flux integral of a vector field through a given oriented surface.
            </description>
        </outcome>
        <outcome>
            <title>Stokes' and Divergence Theorem</title>
            <slug>VC8</slug>
            <path>outcomes/VC/VC8</path>
            <description>
                Use Stokes’ Theorem (resp. Divergence Theorem) to relate a flux integral with a line integral (resp. triple integral).
            </description>
        </outcome>     
        
        
        

    <!-- Sample outcomes for testing -->
        <outcome>
            <title>Sample Outcome</title>
            <slug>EX1</slug>
            <path>outcomes/EX1</path>
            <description>
Simplify the sum of two monomials.
            </description>
        </outcome>
        <outcome>
            <title>Sample Image Outcome</title>
            <slug>IMG1</slug>
            <path>outcomes/IMG1</path>
            <description>
Example of generating graphics.
            </description>
        </outcome>
    </outcomes>
</bank>